"Cities and Their Specificities: Standards, Customs and the Making of 21st‐Century Urbanity"
Mass Customisation and Standardisation: An Urban Dialectic
Towards a Distinctive Urbanism: An Interview with Kenneth Frampton
Miesian Grids and the Domain of Ink
Standardising Heterogeneity: Public Housing and the Absent(ed) Architect
From Mass Customisation to Design ‘Democratisation’
On Modelling Complexity and Urban Form
"Contemporary Architecture Practice: Samsung Raemian Housing Masterplan, Haan River, Seoul, Korea"
(In)formational Cities
"Growth Typologies, Localities and Defamiliarisation: Experiments with Artificial Urbanism in Sichuan, Guangzhou and Beijing"
"Rocker‐Lange Architects: Shanghai Lilong Tower Urbanism, Shanghai, China"
Permanence and Change
"davidclovers: The Repulse Bay Complex, Repulse Bay, Hong Kong"
Catalytic Urbanism: The Role of Customised Design Solutions in Delivering Transformational Urban Change
"OCEAN CN Consultancy Network: Second Development Zone, Umekita Area, Osaka, Japan"
Engineering Urban Complexity: Bespoke Integrated Design
"Archi‐Union Architects, City of Breeze, Shenzhen Bay, Shenzhen, China"
"Technological Transitions, Industrial Innovations and the Marching Chinese Urban Revolution: An Interview with Jerry Ku and Philip Vernon of E‐Grow, Shanghai"
"Gramazio Kohler Research, Automated Diversity: New Morphologies of Vertical Urbanism"
Cities on the Edge of Chaos
Fusing the Computational and the Physical: Towards a Novel Material Culture
The New Materiality
The New Science of Form‐Searching
The New Cyber‐Physical Making in Architecture: Computational Construction
Self‐X Materials and Structures in Nature and Technology: Bio‐inspiration as a Driving Force for Technical Innovation
Fibrous Tectonics
ICD/ITKE Research Pavilion 2012: Coreless Filament Winding Based on the Morphological Principles of an Arthropod Exoskeleton
ICD/ITKE Research Pavilion 2013‐14: Modular Coreless Filament Winding Based on Beetle Elytra
ICD/ITKE Research Pavilion 2014–15: Fibre Placement on a Pneumatic Body Based on a Water Spider Web
Performative Wood: Physically Programming the Responsive Architecture of the HygroScope and HygroSkin Projects
Structural Stone Surfaces: New Compression Shells Inspired by the Past
Membrane Morphologies: Heterogeneous Forces and Articulated Material Form
Granular Morphologies: Programming Material Behaviour with Designed Aggregates
Fabrication Agency: Landesgartenschau Exhibition Hall
Templating Design for Biology and Biology for Design
Hacking Science: The ALivE Group's Material Design Methods for Interdisciplinary Environments
"Computational Design and Automotive Material Gestalt: Cross‐disciplinary Design Research by the Mercedes‐Benz Center of Advanced Design and the Institute for Computational Design (ICD), University of Stuttgart"
Macrofabrication with Digital Materials: Robotic Assembly
Actualising (Overlooked) Material Capacities
2050: Can You Imagine … ?
Designing a Graceful Ending: A Conversation with Design Luminary Paola Antonelli
Prejudicial Narratives: Building Tomorrow's World Today
Design Is Our Answer: An Interview with Leading Design Thinker Tim Brown
"Welcome to the Third Industrial Revolution: The Mass‐Customisation of Architecture, Practice and Education"
After Architects: A Vision of the Near Future from SHoP
"Her, With the Hammer: A Mother's Letter to Her Daughter"
"It's Not Where You're From, It's Where You're At"
The Street As Platform: How Digital Dynamics Shape the Physical City
A Century of Ecological Innovation
Sentient Futures: The Hydra Trilogy by Future Cities Lab
"Interdependence: A Manifesto for Our Urban Future, Together"
Healthy Humane Buildings
Media Network: Three Moments From the Future Post‐Manufacturing Supply Chain
Empowering Communities Through Design
Heaven on Earth
El Sur Global: Future Resilient City
Captain Nemo's Dream
Bricked House: How Code and Law Can Lock You Out
"Looking Back on a Radical Idea: The Buranest Cooperative Rural New Town, Amhara, Ethiopia"
The Generous City
To a Curator of Beautiful and Healthy Lives: A Note to Myself
The Art of Prediction
"Pavilions, Pop‐Ups and Parasols: Are They Platforms for Change?"
In the Pursuit of Pleasure: The Not so Fleeting Life of the Pavilion and its Ilk
Castles and Pavilions: Creating New Hybrid Places of Exchange
A Sketchbook for the City to Come: The Pop‐Up as R&D
Folly Variations: The Time‐Specific Architecture of Mass Studies
100 Year City (Maribor): The Virtual Concourse Reframed
"Not to be Taken Seriously: Kiosks, Roadside Joys and Other Things That are Beneath Architectural Contempt"
Barcelona Reset: Circuit of Ephemeral Architecture
Building Community
Global Village Media: Coming Together in the Early 1970s at Whiz Bang Quick City
"When a Tree House No Longer Says ‘House’, Are We Virtually There?"
Agents for Urban Food Education and Security
Architecture of the Occasion
Indeterminacy & Contingency: The Seroussi Pavilion and Bloom by Alisa Andrasek
Urban Phenomenon: Guerilla Architecture in Taipei
The Affirmative Qualities of a Temporal Architecture
Lasting Impressions: Pop‐Up Culture by HWKN
"Entrepreneur Makers: Digitally Crafted, Crowdfunded Pavilions"
From the Subversive to the Serious: Temporary Urbanism as a Positive Force
"Relating Perceptions of Construction, Experimental and Local"
Past and Present Trajectories of Experimental Architectures
Building In and Out of Place
The Bauhaus: Case Study Experiments in Education
The Open City and the e[ad] School of Architecture and Design
Rural Studio: Incarnations of a Design‐and‐Build Programme
Architecture by Latitude and Locality: The Scarcity and Creativity Studio
Koshirakura Landscape Workshop. In Search of Context: Working With The Force Of Erasure
Detoured Installations: The Policies and Architecture of the Norwegian National Tourist Routes Project
Conviction Into Tectonics: The Work of Rintala Eggertsson
TYIN tegnestue Architects. Integrating On‐Site Education and Practice
Renzo Piano: Poet of Technology
Studio Mumbai. The Practice of Making
The Builder's Name: SHoP and the Ethics of Knowledge Transfer
Informed Non‐Standard. En Route to Performative
Auxiliary Architectures: Augmenting Existing Architectures with Performative Capacities
A Developmental Route to Local Specificity. Nested Catenaries
Smart Living Architecture: Solar Prototypes. IAAC Endesa Pavilion Barcelona
Outlook: En Route to Intensely Local Architectures and Tectonics
Sustaining the Local: An Alternative Approach to Sustainable Design
The Gulf Urbanisation
Museum Development in the Gulf: Narrative and Architecture
Cultural Exchange and Urban Appropriation: Spaces for Art in Sharjah's Historical Centre
Design for the Future: Educational Institutions in the Gulf
A City for Education
The Evolution of Tall Building in the Gulf: From the Sensational to the Sensitive
Drawing on Sand: Cities in the Making
"Inexhaustible Ambition: Two Eras of Planning in Doha, Qatar"
New Hearts for Two Gulf Cities
Future Flyovers: Dubai in 1971
Urban and Architectural Sustainability in the Gulf
Fast Forwards: 10 Years of Sustainable Initiatives in the Gulf Region
Performative Urbanism: An Emerging Model of the Gulf
The Struggle for Integrity: Emerging Local Practices in the Gulf
A Field of Possibilities: The Post‐Oil Future of Bahrain
