Architecture and Beauty: A Symbiotic Relationship
Beauty in Architecture: Not a Luxury ‐ Only a Necessity
Truth and Beauty: The Role of Aesthetics in Mathematics and Physics
The Return of Beauty: Driving a Wedge Between Objects and Qualities
Abstraction and Informality Generate a New Aesthetic An Interview with Kazuyo Sejima
New Solids and Massive Forms
"Which Beauty Will Guide Us? Seeking a Reflective, Sustainable, Socially Engaged Visual Culture"
Chromatic Compositions: Design Dissonance and the Aesthetic of Fusion
Beauty as Ecological Intelligence: Bio‐digital Aesthetics as a Value System of Post‐Anthropocene Architecture
The Primacy of Relationships and the Reclamation of Beauty Jeanne Gang: Observed and Interviewed
The Geometry of Seduction: Considerations of Beauty from Noun to Verb
"A Specific Theory of Models: The Posthuman Beauty of Weird Scales, Snowglobes and Supercomponents"
"Ambiguous, Bipolar Beauty: And Similarly Agile and Fragile Post‐Digital Practices"
Deep Immediacy: Programming Beauty
"Beauty is in the Back Story: Diversity, Complexity and Collaborative Making in the Australian Condition"
In Search of the Unseen: Towards Superhuman Intuition
In Part Whole: The Aesthetics of the Discrete
‘A Rose by Any Other Name Would Smell as Sweet’: Finding Beauty in the Past Century
Enduring Experiments: How the Architectural Avant‐Garde Lives On
Superstudio as Super‐Office: The Labour of Radical Design
"Function Follows Form: Some Affinities Between Pure Icons, Hardcore Architecture and OOO"
"Avant‐Garde in the Age of Identity: Alvin Boyarsky, the Architectural Association and the Impact of Pegadogy"
The Little Big Planet of Architectural Imagination: An Interview with NEMESTUDIO's Neyran Turan
"Feedback Loops: Or, Past Futures Haunt Architecture's Present"
Archive of Affinities Making Architecture from Architecture
Avant‐Garde Legacies: A Spirited Flâneur
System Cities: Building a ‘Quantitative Utopia’
The Function of Utopia
"Feverish Delirium: Surrealism, Deconstruction and Numinous Presences"
Behind the Wheel: Charles Darwin and Superstudio Do the Driving
Play it Again: In Conversation with Architect Sam Jacob and Artist Pablo Bronstein
"Architecture Between the Panels: Comics, Cartoons and Graphic Narrative in the (New) Neo Avant‐Garde"
Copying as Cultural Iconoclasm
Anticipating the Digital: The Game of Supersurface
What Comes After the Avant‐ Garde?
Embracing Research in the Business of Architecture
Prologue: A Shared Practice
Resituated Research: Achieving Meaningful Impact on the Fault Line Between Academia and Practice
Public Planning Reimagined: Building Capacity and Agency
Practise What You Preach: The University as a Common Ground Between Research and its Application
Spanning Continuums: Addressing the Separation of Research and Practice in Architecture
Out of Practice: Theoretical Speculations In and Out of the Business of Architecture
Mitigation of Shock: Post‐Occupancy Anthropology
How Is It For You? Building Design as Experienced by Users and Makers
Vertically Integrated Research: An Unusual Business Model
Pushing the Envelope: Innovation and Collaboration at Bloomberg's New European Headquarters
For the Public Good: Rebuilding the Architectural Profession's Social Contract
Research Infiltration: The Germination of Preoccupations
Deconstructing Research: A Reverse‐Engineering Methodology and Practice
Building Practices: The Infrastructure of Materials Research
Translating Culture: Framing Indigenous Knowledge Through Architecture
Collective Impressions of Smithson Plaza: Weaving History with the Present
Towards a New Normal: The Blurred Landscape of Architectural Research in China
"Less Grey, More Black and White: Architecture Needs a Consistent Platform in Research"
Discrete Architecture in the Age of Automation
The Origins of Discretism: Thinking Unthinkable Architecture
Architecture for the Commons: Participatory Systems in the Age of Platforms
Mereological Thinking: Figuring Realities within Urban Form
Bits and Pieces: Digital Assemblies: From Craft to Automation
Our Automated Future: A Discrete Framework for the Production of Housing
Rubens Structures: A Different Lightness Through Performance Adaptability
Distributed Fabrication: Cooperative Making with Larger Groups of Smaller Machines
Discrete Flexibility: Computing Lightness in Architecture
Et Alia: A Projective History of the Architectural Discrete
"Particlised: Computational Discretism, or The Rise of the Digital Discrete"
Complicit: The Creation Of and Collaboration With Intelligent Machines
Discrete Sampling: There is No Object or Field … Just Statistical Digital Patterns
Series and Other Unit‐Based Alternatives: Notes on Contemporary Digital Operations
"Soft Discrete Familiars: Animals, Blankets and Brick, Oh My!"
The Discrete Charm of the Glitch
Meta‐Utopia and the Box: Two Stories about Avante‐Garde Projects
There Is No Such Thing as a Digital Building: A Critique of the Discrete
Neo‐Machine: Architecture Without People
Further Trace Effects of the Post‐Anthropocene
Invisible Images: Your Pictures Are Looking at You
Calibration Camouflage
Territorial Robots
Where Tomorrow Arrives Today: Infrastructure as Processional Space
A Place for Everything
Human Exclusion Zones: Logistics and New Machine Landscapes
Where the Internet Lives John Gerrard: Farm
Museum in the Countryside: Aesthetics of the Data Centre
A Benediction for the Amazon Wind Farm Texas: Where the Landscapes of Resource‐and Data Extraction Meet
Tending Goats and Microprocessors Xingzhe Liu: Uncovering Sichuan's Remote Bitcoin Mines
Fringes of Technology and Spaces of Entanglement in the Pearl River Delta
Regarding the Pain of SpotMini: Or What a Robot's Struggle to Learn Reveals about the Built Environment
"No One's Driving: Autonomous Vehicles Will Reshape Cities, but is Anyone Taking Control of How?"
Disciplinary Hybrids: Retail Landscapes of the Post‐Human City
Ghosts in the Machine: Space Junk and the Future of Earth Orbit
"‘I'm a Cloud of Infinitesimal Data Computation’ When Machines Talk Back: An interview with Deborah Harrison, one of the personality designers of Microsoft's Cortana AI"
Emissaries: A Trilogy of Simulations
"Not For Us: Squatting the Ruins of Our Robot Utopia: An Interview with Paul Inglis, Supervising Art Director of Blade Runner 2049"
Ambiguous Territory Design for a World Estranged